ELIAS SPECTOR-ZABUSKY

SUMMARY

Software engineer and musician working with the MERN stack, with an interest in backend development, full stack development, and product work. Previous experience in project management, operations, and the arts. Strong skills in creative problem-solving and collaboration. Analytically minded with a knack for supporting decision-making.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sept. 2023 – Present

ENGAGE PARTNERS; REMOTE

Develop features and implement site integrations in **TypeScript** and **React** for a text content generator web extension (<u>Click2.ai</u>) powered by generative AI. Provide project management for the development team.

- Designed and built the post generator and integrated this component with LinkedIn and Twitter.
- Iteratively extended settings page to add support for further use cases and per-user configuration.
- Implemented reusable library functions for dynamic, site-agnostic menu creation to enable streamlined future domain integrations and quick and efficient customizations for new applications.

PROFESSIONAL MUSICIAN

Nov. 2015 – Present

FREELANCE; NEW YORK, NEW YORK

Band-member, producer, songwriter, and/or arranger for a few NYC-based bands. www.stolenjars.com

DIGITAL CONTENT AND MERCHANDISE MANAGER

Nov. 2020 – Jan. 2023

ROBIN BARON DESIGN; NEW YORK, NEW YORK

Spearheaded product operations and served as Shopify admin for an interior designer's eCommerce business.

- Utilized HTML and CSS to maintain and customize site, including developing CSS features for the blog.
- Managed 8-10 freelancers in the upload of 12,500+ SKUs from ~40 vendors in line with growth roadmap.

PROJECTS

FRAiME | github.com/ColdWeatherBoyy/Fraime | www.FRAiMED.art

Full Stack Developer. FRAiME is an in-development eCommerce site, leveraging OpenAI's text-to-image DALL-E API to allow users to generate unique art and order prints. **MERN**, **Next.js**, **Styled Components**.

- Co-planned the backend architecture; built majority of REST API endpoints and DB models.
- Improved state management to decrease DB calls by moving data from global context to caching.

Dada Art Museum | github.com/ColdWeatherBoyy/dada-museum | dada-museum.herokuapp.com

Full Stack Developer. Co-designed and implemented UI for a sample museum's homepage with a focus on functional features and dynamic, engaging content. **Node.js**, **React**, **Express**, **Chakra UI**.

- Built Current Exhibits and Featured Artist sections; designed reusable components for consistent site UX.
- Implemented random art feature, making calls to the Art Institute of Chicago's API on click or page load.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Technologies: JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, GraphQL, HTML5, CSS3

Backend: Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, MySQL, Sequelize

Frontend: React, Chakra UI, Next.js, Bootstrap

Misc. Tools: Figma, Insomnia, Git, GitHub, Jest, MS Excel, Google Analytics, Shopify

EDUCATION

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY, NEW YORK, NEW YORK

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

Feb. 2023 – Apr. 2023

HARVARD BUSINESS SCHOOL ONLINE

C. C. C. D. C. A. 1.C.

2011 - 2015

Jan. 2023 – Apr. 2023

Certificate in Business Analytics

BROWN UNIVERSITY, PROVIDENCE, RHODE ISLAND

Bachelor of Arts in Theatre Arts and Performance Studies

Phi Beta Kappa; T. Carpenter Elocution Award